dude this must have been the most badass
POC video for this you know like just
see the thing just there's more there's
more I mean I was going to ask about
this is like a this is like a freaking
uh you know like you know blowout sail
but wait there's
[Music]
more
all righty Yousef dude you're probably
one of our top requested guests that we
get on the Pod so thanks for coming on
and welcome uh hi uh thanks for having
me uh I really enjoy your podcast and
your show awesome dude that that's great
um so yeah we just for for context for
the for the viewers we are here in sunny
Miami for H1 1305 and we're getting to
do a live interview with Yousef samuda
am I pronouncing that right yeah it's
samuda but it's the same yeah I'm TR I
tried but uh what they oh there's some
construction going on or something um
but uh yeah dude super excited to have
you so many people have requested and
your blog is absolutely legendary um so
definitely looking forward to this one I
wanted to start us off um with this
episode with kind of discussing
obviously client side stuff is your your
passion you know one of the things you
love the most if we look at your at your
um at your you know writeups that you've
done on your blog um and so I I kind of
want to get a little bit more niched
down inside of that and understand that
a little bit more what kind of client
side
things makes your you know your pulse go
up what what kind of thing are we
talking post messages are we talking
about hash like what what kind of things
within client side stuff are your is
your favorite to work with Okay so uh
basically when uh I do look in client
side stuff uh I view it of course
initially as a back Bounty Hunter so I
look for stuff that pays off the best so
maybe I look uh to anything related to
oath So eventually I can uh Escalade to
have an
atto uh also uh so it would be maybe
post message maybe uh like uh leaking
the hash the with
token o token yeah so that that makes
sense there's there's there's there's
definitely a lot of areas of client side
stuff where where that sort of stuff
comes into play and if you look at your
blog it's just an array of okay we've
got a hash leak we've got a post message
but we got xss we got everything all
over the place so um but but for you
it's mostly focused on let me see what
this application does and let me see how
I can you know optimize this for the
goal of account takeover is that that's
that's pretty much where you end up
right so the final goal is to find an
account takeover so sometimes it would
be like you said post message sometimes
it's even a self xss so if I see a
chance to uh let's say find a self xss
and from there up upgrade it to an atto
I do that very interesting so uh is most
of your hunting focused around atto like
is that pretty much your primary target
all the time or do you ever go for like
xss or because you mentioned like a self
xss is that what you're looking for or
is it kind of just along the way yeah so
with client side bags the Maximum Impact
you can reach is uh basically a account
account takeover so if you find uh find
it through an xss or self xss or a
combination of uh because when we say
self xss It's a combination of Logan
logo csrf combined with that self xss
and post messages oh so all of that uh
uh eventually you
the biggest impact you'll reach is
account take over okay gotcha nice and I
just want to make sure make sure you're
keeping the mic a consistent distance
from your he's got this nice you know
deep voice and I want to make sure that
the uh the mic Pi picks it up um no that
makes sense you know and he says
essentially uh yeah I just try to go for
the max impact possible on the client
side you know just don't give up until I
have
everything that's great um that's
awesome dude and and so I guess um I
wanted to talk about specifically I want
to go and talk about some bugs right off
the bat um there was one blog post you
did and and I think this is one of your
most recent ones uh uh and you haven't
blogged as much over the past uh year or
two um but this is the last one on on
meta and it was a client side race
condition via post message and this one
caught my attention because this is
something that I've kind of been
researching a little bit and I was like
oh you know I wonder if this is possible
and and I started you know standing up
some things in a lab and I started
playing with it and it it seems very
possible and then I stumbled upon this
blog and I'm just like Frick yousef's
already done it um so I was wondering
you know have you had obviously this was
an amazing write up and and an amazing
bug have you had similar um scenarios
like that before where you see
essentially State changing actions
happening with post message that will
allow you to trigger race conditions in
the flow that's happening on the other
tab yeah so with that one if we can
explain more about it so it was like uh
uh an NPC communication between uh
Facebook and uh if frame hosting the
game in apps. face.com so basically what
it does uh it uh requests uh the third
party uh or the game page request to the
parent uh uh the o o token for that app
and Facebook should reply with that
token uh what they did at that time they
check the app ID the client ID so not
any app would uh request o token of
other apps uh they did that check
correctly but uh what I found out that
uh if we specify for example another app
uh uh they'll check the origin in the
server s so for example if uh Candy
Crash requested the O token for
Instagram app uh it would say fail
eventually because uh the origin has to
be set to candy
crash.com and that would fail in the
server side so what I did was uh
initially make the request uh with
instagram.com origin uh and they had
like some kind of client side function
that would change the origin check so
because it's an asynchronous request to
uh to uh to the server
to the server request so because of that
uh while waiting for the response of
that request I'll just uh make the
client side uh uh that client side post
message to change the origin and now
like uh because it already made the
checks of the origin initially now they
completely trust that origin so when it
cames back it'll just send it to uh
dude I I freaking love it man so the
whole thing is tied to essentially that
like window instance or the whatever
like where it's coming from yeah that
reference and then it's just all
basically goes from there once it
establishes that sort of trust with with
that session or that window wherever the
messages are coming from then from there
it's basically blind and yeah yeah so
they do a lot of checks initially of the
origin on all of that uh and uh after
that they make the request to uh get the
O token and uh after getting it in their
response they'll just uh like they don't
do checks anymore they'll just uh send
it back to whatever origin to whatever
window uh the source window and setting
the post message to that origin ah so
they're using the built-in post message
the second parameter in the post message
right a lot of time for the attackers us
it's star but for some people when
they're trying to control what origin
they're sending it to that second
parameter is the origin that they're
going to allow the message to yeah sent
to is that right yeah yeah so that
second parameter to set the target
origin uh I change it while the while
the request is the response is being uh
dud retor I love that and and so one I
just kind of wanted to brainstorm with
you a little bit about that type of bug
um obviously that one's that one's a
great one you have an an asynchronous
you know post message they can go
through and change essentially the
origin that's allowed to receive the
post message on the way back while
they're while they've already done the
checks um
so that's great um one of the ones that
I was kind of thinking of is when
there's a
window. uh opener check okay of of An
Origin right and what I was thinking was
wouldn't it be interesting if we had
three tabs okay we've got attacker
control tab opened tab Vic you know
victim tab right and when this third tab
does a window. opener
check uh the original tab redirects this
guy to a cach page on on the uh on the
parent on the site that's allowed right
so it does window. opener. you know
location. or whatever that that's valid
because it's the same origin and then
real quickly our first tab redirects the
second one back um to attacker control
domain before this guy does a post
message to him to intercept the post
message right and and one of the things
that I I did so but like you mentioned
in your write up the whole rub here is
there has to be
a you know a delay some action that
takes time um and normally that's going
to be an HTTP request right because
you'll get a couple hundred milliseconds
of time to to trigger your exploit um
and one of the ways I figured out to
optimize this was uh forcing the browser
to Cache some of these pages so when the
the first page does the redirect of the
second page that doesn't start another
HTTP request it loads it straight from
the browser cache so it's an
instantaneous switch so if you send a
post message to a tab that's loading
what happens does it hang like does it
fail I think it fails okay uh so what's
the question if I if I send a post
message like say I redirect the second
tab to some other domain and I send a
post message while it's redirecting
while it's redirecting yeah because
there are no uh so there are no uh uh uh
cross origin uh uh event listeners uh
for messages so there are none set yet
so the post message would be
nothing to receive it yeah so so so the
key here is making sure that you get
that that timing correctly and the and
the way that I figured out to do that in
my research was you know getting the
browser to Cache your HTML page you know
with some specific caching headers and
then you redirect that page that will be
receiving the post message right before
the post message gets sent and then your
cashed HTML page is already there
listening yeah you know what it also
makes me wonder is if you could take
advantage of certain like if it's
parsing Json maybe you give it a really
like deep dense Json blob that takes it
a second to parse so that you could
actually use some built-in functionality
to force a delay in just processing time
not even like you know caching and stuff
but you know how long does it take for
it to load this giant Json object uh so
yeah uh after the bag I found in
Facebook I actually found a bypass for
that and uh basically the bypass was uh
uh a part of the pipas was to uh try to
uh like uh escalate the time needed to
uh so we can uh so they applied to a Lo
mechanism so when the request is sent uh
there is a lock so we need time to like
trick it to not trigger the lock so I
did that by uh uh I guess sending a lot
of post message requests like a ton of
them with like each one 5 megabytes or
something like that and that uh did the
trick no way yeah yeah dude that's so
cool I I did something similar once with
a post message bug on PayPal um and
essentially it was a a scenario where I
needed to win a race to to a an if frame
on a victim page right um to send the
configuration right and I needed to get
a post message first and get an ID and
then win the race with the with the
other post message back to that child
post message and the way that I won it
was a by not using Json parse by using
string um yeah direct yeah exactly like
uh substring right and so I knew that
the ID was always at you know index 23
or whatever right so directly exactly so
just grab it substring Go and whereas
the the other if frame that was sending
it was using Json parse and doing some
other stuff which takes more Cycles so
there's lots of fun ways that we can do
all sorts of cool stuff like that so I
mean obviously this bypass sounds pretty
freaking amazing I I've never thought
about sending you know massive massive
uh post messages to kind of bog down the
side have you have you done any other
stuff with uh with post message uh raise
conditions or just those two I think
it's a pretty rare class yeah so uh it's
actually the post message is uh just
like uh the communication part uh now
I'll let you turn that
off good yeah no worri uh so uh it's
actually like sometimes you'll find uh
so I view post message uh like event
listener message event listener of post
message as uh a source uh yeah so
basically it can happen from the URL
sometimes you can find the race
condition uh so let's say on has change
event when the hash is changed uh it
will uh trigger some uh stuff like uh it
would grab some text from uh the current
location. ref and try to uh uh purse it
and all of that so I guess sometimes uh
there are uh uh rejects checks and uh
What uh you can do is uh R condition the
reject check uh of the of the has change
right again large data what the heck
yeah yeah it's but it's like uh it's uh
very time um uh since yeah yeah yeah so
it's not uh
I tried it it worked like maybe once in
a thousand yeah it's very low percent
Rex bombing is a thing right like where
you can create like you know really hard
things for re yeah yeah so you can is
that basically what you have to do is
like create like a payload that is
really hard for the Rex to work with so
that it takes the amount of time that
you need it to take so no so the Rex
basically checks uh the for example
let's say it checks the URL uh of uh if
of a text from a text and if it passes
it would do something for example set
window. location. to that URL so
basically uh I'll raise condition the
check of
the the reject check and the
window.location so because
that so it it would pass the rejects
after passing the rejects instantly it
would change it's no wonder it was like
one in a thousand right because the the
the timing on that I mean it's there
probably wasn't even a line between it
right yeah a line but uh you can uh
force it uh also you can brute force it
because uh it's a client side uh uh code
so you can make it like the page won't
reload it doesn't in this case it
doesn't need to reload so you can do it
like thousand 100,000 times I I think
it's really I think those are really
cool types of bugs too because you can
use sort of like I think maybe
technically it's a pop under sort of
thing for that where you you open up a
page right and now the user is
interacting with this page but then you
can do this attack on the window that
you just came from right and because
you've got a frame reference and you can
you know brute force them I use that
often in in these sort of scenarios
because you know you need some
explanation on why the users sitting
there for you know 5 10 seconds while
you're BR forcing obviously if it was
only a thousand then it would it
wouldn't take very long on the Cent side
perspective but um you know if you're
doing brute forcing something a little
bit more intense like I've had to brute
force a six-digit code before uh via VIA
post message which is very doable yeah
it's very fast it's instantaneous yeah
um which was something that I did not
expect um so that that's definitely an
an extremely cool bug class yeah well
it's funny because post message is one
of those things where it's like you're
almost making a request but you're not
so like the possibilities with it are so
much larger like like it's so fast
because you don't have to make HTP
requests every single time and so this
extra functionality that they like made
as you know user flow ease of use
whatever like it's now the Hacker's
Advantage oh yeah did you know like
before post message it was like the two
pages were communicating using window.
name they still have so sometimes you
can still use that for exploits um
especially when you need to uh get a a
payload into a like a heavy CSP
environment I don't know if you've ever
done that but like you know you set the
window name and then you can you can
transfer it away and and access it so
it's it's a it's that's definitely a
nice gadget for transferring data across
um quickly but man is it a pain in the
butt though and I'm glad we have post
message now instead of window name um so
you me you mentioned I want to go back
to something you mentioned before you
said um and and I don't know why I've
never really like thought of it this way
but uh you mentioned the onh change
event like of course I I don't know why
that hasn't been in my client
perspective of looking for window. Adent
listener hash you know and so that's
another that's another great source and
I I'm wondering actually and I don't
know off the top of my head can window.
opener change the hash of the other page
without redirecting the page without
like refreshing yeah without refreshing
I have uh stories later you want to hear
them let dude let's do it man yeah I
want to hear it right now so uh
basically uh do you know like when you
go to Google and search for couple of
words or my gosh I I love how this story
is is starting okay so when you search
for and pops up uh like an article uh
when you click on the article it will
automatically uh scroll down to that
particular paragraph Yes so this is like
technology known uh as uh scroll to text
fragment it's supported by Chrome uh so
basically
uh is it a chrome only feature uh I
guess it's Chrome like the last time I
checked it's only Chrome okay uh so
basically you specify in the hash part
like you put colon SL colon text equals
and you put like suffix and prefix and
suffix and uh basically Chrome will look
in that page uh for that paragraph or
that uh stuff and scroll directly to
that one so uh what how I abused this
and actually this is was zero day in
Chrome back then when uh I used it it's
reported on yeah yeah yeah dude this is
great I love I love this yeah and we
want to talk about this too because you
found some other browser boxs but yeah
can continue yes yeah so basically what
I did was uh trying to uh let's say look
in the page for certain words for uh
let's say uh like
uh you can't look for csrf toen you
won't find it as text yeah but we'll
talk about this uh so what I did first
you have to detect the scroll so uh so
is this a cross-site leak is that what
this is or yeah it's a cross-site leak
uh of this is so smart why did I not
think to look at this yeah yeah but uh
here comes the part of the redirecting
window to the opener and changing the
hash so this uh check of like every time
the hash Chang uh you look in the page
and scroll if you find the text it would
only happen if uh the hash was changed
from same origin uh domain interesting
so uh so you can do it for example from
attacker.com window. opener.
location ref equals and only change the
hash right it won't work because uh if
it's cross origin domain it would
require each time to change user uh it
would re require user gesture every time
mhm uh would it work if there was a
cross origin policy set in the headers
on the domain like could you update it
like is it blocking you purely because a
browser security or is it specific to
this feature specific to this feature uh
it won't do the scrolling the searching
of the text and then scroll unless the
hash was changed by uh same origin uh
domain so the first part of the attack
is to find uh uh a page let's say in
facebook.com that would uh we can
control to set window. opener to a
certain URL so for example we can set uh
make this page return window. opener
equals
https uh
facebook.com/ certain endpoint sure uh
it won't allow for example JavaScript
your schem but still allows
facebook.com and of course you just had
that in your pocket you know yeah I had
that so
yeah I had that and uh of course this is
this is why let me just this is why we
really highly encourage going deep on
programs right like like this this sort
of a masterpiece of a situation where
Yousef comes up with a like a browser
Quirk and then you need the specific
piece of function if you know an
application especially one as big as as
Facebook inside outside upside down then
you'll you'll have a list of these and
I'm sure you keep a list of of gadgets
as well you know of things that you
found that are like ah this could
probably be helpful someday but I don't
have a you know a use for right now this
is something that I think not enough
people do and if they would then they'd
see a lot bigger success in the bug
Bounty realm yeah so sometimes you see
something interesting in uh in like
client side code or even an in point
that returns something and you just
ignore it you feel like it's inter but
you ignore it but uh I advise anyone to
just save it in a note for example one
time in during uh live hacking event
with Facebook I didn't find any bags I
just went through the notes and I found
you know that post message uh xss do xss
the one that like I have a page uh uh
yeah you're going to have to be more
specific you if you have a lot of post
message
DXs so uh just let's not
go yeah yeah I forgot that one but uh I
just found it from the note like I just
went through and I got second uh place
that that's crazy man yeah I do I do
remember that now yeah I thinking like
he's like yeah you remember that one
time I got domx sis I was like yeah yeah
I I can think of a
couple yeah um but yeah okay so back to
Yeah so basically with this one as I
said uh you need to have uh uh the
redirect or the change of the hash from
uh same origin domain if you have that
uh you can basically search in the page
uh it would scroll to a certain uh part
of the page if uh it finds the that word
uh the second
uh and this is the zero day it was I was
like how do you leak that though yeah so
it was like how to uh if I I frame that
page p and uh when I I frame that page
you know sometimes when the if frame
scroll the main window with scroll too
yeah yeah it happens so I was able to
detect the scroll in the if frame with
the scroll in the parent uh window so
with that I can uh uh uh like have a
confirmation if word is found in the
iframe or not uh yeah this the dude
that's crazy e so
okay so would scroll on the parent would
you scroll on the parent page or on the
I frame so the frame the scroll will
would happen if the word was found using
the scroll to text fragment if the word
was found in the text it will scroll in
the if frame but uh unexpectedly Chrome
also scrolled the parent uh window so
both of them scrolled and would it do
both on load because you can put it in
the URL right and it would just
like if you put the iframe URL as that
text with the text hash fragment okay it
would scroll to that text in the iframe
yeah okay but that scroll triggered the
scroll in the parent as soon as it loads
yeah yeah so also because you freaking
way yeah yeah that's uh one allowed me
to like basically load any page in a KN
frame and search that page and detect if
the word was found or not wow
wow and the the only requirement being
that you need a gadget where you can set
the the uh make like uh a client side
rir from that domain so for example a
page that would do window. opener uh
location. equals uh that domain with the
hash and that would it's yeah that that
that's actually not a very uncommon
situation with with post message related
stuff I think too being able to do hash
based redirections uh or injections into
window location. has um and so but it
can be window location. has not window
location.href or does it have to be href
yeah it can be hash W but it's rare to
find has yeah yeah yeah and also it can
be like the same page with the set
window.location it's not like opener
setting opener yeah well I I I say it is
it is I guess it's rare to see window
location
but it's less rare to see Pages where
you can um do where you can control the
the routing in like these sort of client
side page routing situations right you
know where where you've got like um this
whole route table that's set up for the
hash fragment right so if you have a
gadget where you can uh control that
then well but I guess it depends on
whether the yeah because you would need
the well if you're not trying to leak
something that changes then you can do
it over multiple refreshes yeah yeah so
so dude that's that's nuts man sometimes
uh you can do it with the refreshes but
sometimes because uh for example uh this
is the like there are more there's more
to the story so yeah okay sometimes if
you can uh let's say
uh return the row page so you can change
content type set to text uh uh text
plane so now won't be rendered as HTML
so now you have access to dat uh you can
you have access to the csrf Token you
can query it I was going to ask yeah
yeah yeah so the whole thing is now text
so now you can search text anywhere
within the whole thing but but you still
need the gadget don't you yeah but the
gadget not in that page if you found
like the gadget that would uh let's say
facebook.com has an endpoint uh that
endpoint return to JavaScript that would
do window. open opener. location. equals
and you control that part so now you can
change the that page opener page to this
uh like the one that ah dude what the
heck so uh this is crazy so then you've
got that middle page and then you're
using so every time I want to uh no I'm
thinking about it wrong yeah every time
I want to change the hash in that page
to make to look for award I to it yeah
so I just reload the end point that has
window. opener. location. I just reload
it change the value of the right the
value set and it would make uh it would
make the change in the other uh page
because the event has to it has to be
triggered by a change right so you have
to change the hatch or you have to
change the it has to be changed by same
origin uh domain right so it requires
some other vul you can't just load the
URL once because that doesn't change
like the hash isn't changing but if you
load a URL that then changes the hash
that triggers an on hash change event
which then you can pick up and it
Scrolls and then you can use that so
that's happens it's not like JavaScript
code but the browser detects on hash I'm
seeing it now man dude this must have
been the most badass P video for this
you know like just see the thing just
yeah but there's more there's more I
mean I was going to ask about this is
like this is like a freaking uh you know
like you know blowout sale but wait
there's more no this is great yeah so
the stf the scroll to text fragment it
detects words so it doesn't detect
character by character so uh it's words
like for example you can like uh reforce
the csrf token because it's uh uh yeah
it's uh like 16 bits or uh whatever uh
you can't uh you can't actually look for
that you need character by character in
you uh in
Chrome the separation of words is using
spaces using uh whatever I guess spaces
and uh period yeah maybe or tabs so what
I did like uh if I can find a way to
change the you uh uh the page encoding
for example if it's not specifically set
to utf8 in uh in containt type if I can
uh control some part of the of that page
I can inject few characters and the
browser would uh assume that it's not UT
utf8 it's utf16 now I'll have like
Chinese words as yeah and Chinese words
like they have like yeah yeah it's
separate and then you can de you can
decode that back down
dude what the heck this is some Matias
Carlson [__] here okay now I need to ask
when you submit something like this to a
triage like what do they understand it
like how how much back and forth do you
have to go through yeah so uh actually
this one didn't uh it wasn't reported uh
some parts were were reported to
facebook.com but this back uh with the
UT with the uni code change and
everything was reported to uh uh that I
can disclose and they had like uh like
sometimes uh hard time uh to understand
it but uh yeah eventually they did and
uh they fixed it wow dude that that's
great and I guess your your reports need
to be very indepth in order for them to
be able to reproduce all that so that's
that's uh that's amazing dude what what
a uh what a great example of the
persistence needed to do this job
because I'm sure you didn't like like
just see all of that I don't know maybe
maybe did but I if I were you I wouldn't
going into that situation I wouldn't
have you know seen that path straight
from the beginning I would have you know
it would have taken me a lot of
iteration on top of all right well now
the you know spacing is wrong how do I
fix that problem you know how do how do
I get this to be a same origin redirect
you know what's going on here so there's
there's a lot of persistence that's
needed there to try to figure out all
those things so sometimes like an advice
if a new feature comes out you just go
to the
uh uh the standard page read it and also
the discussion page in I'm not sure in
GitHub or in Chrome in chome yeah yeah
you'll find like uh documents they share
documents how they uh like uh want to
protect against this uh security threat
how they'll protect against this
sometimes they'll have like uh accepted
risk and that accepted risk you can use
it to uh launch another attack in some
scenarios yeah interesting do do they
ever push back on that because it is
accepted risk because they go well this
is accepted risk so we're not going to
take that yeah but pushed back against
the youf report what are you crazy like
try to die yeah no but uh the Brower
guys thought that is accepted or uh like
for example uh they didn't require user
gesture uh with uh client side rir
originating from same origin domains I
guess now they do so after this with the
brute forcing and everything they do now
so sometimes they they're not convinced
about something and after that uh they
change yeah wow dude that's that's an
awesome story uh so glad we got that one
right in the beginning of this episode
that that's awesome um wow uh I'm I'm
not not gonna lie I'm a little bit
stunned on that I just yeah so I wanted
to ask like it sounds like a lot of your
bugs are very multifaceted like there's
a lot of different aspects there's a lot
of different moving pieces and stuff you
mentioned you take notes how like is it
super detailed notes and how much are
you going back to to those notes because
I imagine as you're hacking you're like
some of it's clicking you're like oh I
have this thing that will work here but
some of it maybe not is is it all just
notes or how how are you keeping track
of that so I just keep a screenshot of
BB like uh or sometimes I just have uh
like uh note that this page returned
let's say uh uh a client side code that
would uh change window. opener okay uh
the other one would make a post message
that I can control uh like control the
contain so that the notes would be like
this like this one allows me to do this
this one allows me to do this and that's
it it's not like deep deep okay that's
cool that's awesome I mean I feel like
everybody I talk to like notes are like
a huge part part because there are so
many like potential things that we come
across that are useful later and I think
the bugs that you submit especially like
I can't think of anybody who does like
that level of chaining and like
vulnerability like combination that you
do I feel like every bug that I see it's
always like there's multiple pieces and
it's it's so creative do you ever dupe
like do do people ever D like no never
no like the last time I D yeah it was in
2018 I guess or 2019
this guy hasn't this guy hasn't duped in
six years that's crazy wow dude that's
that's amazing um so thank you for that
story that's that's great and I kind of
want to come back to your um post
message flow a little bit here okay
so um what kind of what kind of
methodology do you normally use for this
because we've got a couple things uh
I'll sort of State the obvious we'll get
those out of the way so that we can go
into the more interesting stuff you know
you've got when you've got multiple
Pages uh multiple frames you know tabs
or if frames and stuff like that that's
always a place that you're going to want
to look for that sort of post message
based communication um and you've got
you know obviously you can see if you've
got the post message tracker plug-in
installed you can see the post messages
flying between the page and the global
listeners on the side um so like what is
your go-to methodology for identifying
those things you just read the
JavaScript like read the JavaScript stra
straight or are you looking specifically
for the listeners yeah so uh the first
thing I do is uh thanks to friends with
the extension so I just grab I see the
the part of code that said The Listener
I'll just go to the source code and uh
get uh like that part and uh start
looking if it's it looks interesting
like they uh they're accepting some data
they're uh using that data to do
something I'll just continue with the
research otherwise I'll ignore it and
move to the next one so that's it like
One By One MH uh sometimes like if I see
something uh I see for example uh a
listener from Google let's say uh from
uh GS uh like uh the one SDK GS SDK that
uh you include to do like Google
authentication so I just ignore it
because I'm sure I tested before it's
safe so I just ignore it uh I ignore for
example
uh uh ones talking to ey frames that are
third party they send books unless
they're leaking uh some interesting
stuff to that uh third party ey frame
yeah and and in those scenarios too I've
also seen sort of a inverse thing like
if you can pop the thing in the ey frame
then you have you might have the ability
to leverage something back on the parent
frame um you know because that that
listener is EXP expecting something
specifically from that embedded host
right and then you have the ability to
talk to that that parent frame yeah so
if you read the code and see that uh for
example it only accepts uh post messages
from origin let's say uh I'm not sure
plugin uh.com and that origin uh uh is
uh from that if frame uh okay and uh it
has some potential I just go to plug.com
try to find an exess there to inject the
if frame and from the ifame I just
send or directly send and especially on
high pay targets like the ones you're
you're used to working on you know it's
worth that extra effort if you can
guarantee you know if you can open up
your browser Tab and do a post message
you know back or your browser console I
mean and do a post message back up and
verify that there's a bug there if you
can get an xss on that you know child
domain then it's very much worth the
time to go get the xss on that child
domain and then pop those that big bug
by going back up the stack right yeah I
do that like maybe if it's very deep
let's say uh uh if frame and from the ey
frame I have a story about this uh with
Facebook actually and it was very
interesting and it was like uh maybe uh
a Shain of four bags or five bags yes so
uh I'm very interested you got my
attention youf yeah so uh just one more
one more thing with a post message
sometimes like uh you find that there is
a knif frame to plug in or let's say a
logger or Mark you know these if frames
for marketing logging oh yeah all the
time for the clicks and some sometimes
it's not doing something critical but
the parent page is sending critical
information like
window.location is sending it to that if
frame so now I'm interested in the
iframe if I can find an EXs
in that domain hijack frame yeah hijack
the frame receive the
window.location and uh okay it doesn't
have uh lot of data but uh I can for
example do or redirect to that page and
leak it from
there is that something that you often
so I actually had this in my my my list
on the account takeover section because
I want to pick your brain about account
takeover stuff
too like is that send sending off alarms
in your brain when you see okay I can
control the page to which an O an oath
code is being sent to is that is that
often a big thing for you yeah so for
example uh that one actually triggers
okay it depends if I can only Set uh I
can only leak o code to any end point
okay it's interesting now because uh
it's not that interesting actually
because I need to find an endo that
would uh pass it current parameters to
uh to uh redirect or something like that
so I need to find it's easier with hash
because if it's in hash uh I can just
find an open redirect and the browser
will carry the hash 302 right or or like
you need a server side redirect for that
right yeah yeah yeah but with if it's
code uh it needs some work but I accept
it like uh sometimes I'll just uh do it
uh also there are many things that uh
trigger my yeah yeah yeah yeah I wanted
to ask uh well maybe maybe I'll save
this until after but I was going to ask
when you look for account take over is
it always like lowlevel type of post
message like technical bones or are you
looking for like I changed my email on
the profile page and something goes
wrong here like do you do you ever look
at it from sort of the user perspective
or is it always like HTTP browser
JavaScript that that yes so uh so you're
talking about uh account takeover that
can be caused by server side uh Mis
cheaks or misconfigurations yeah I do
that a lot uh but not with the companies
I usually work with like meta because
they have that uh uh yeah you can't
they've kind of got that squared away
yeah but let's say I have few examples
that uh are great actually so for
example let's say uh uh certain
uh uh company uses Facebook uses Apple
uses Google Google uh grave mistake yeah
yeah never use you Facebook in front of
youf yeah yeah so in that case uh you'll
have to for example uh they'll check
after the flow they'll check the email
right they'll not check the user ID or
something else so when they read the
email from Facebook from Apple they
completely trust apple and Facebook and
they just log you in to the to any
account with that email so now if I can
find an email confirmation bypass in
Facebook an email confirmation bypass in
apple I can hijack that company any
account in that company yeah or or or
one of the ones we've seen is like if
you're passing an access token directly
um then sometimes they they will just
check the the email associated with that
not the app associated with that you
seen that one yeah yeah yeah I found it
actually yeah that one uh because they
didn't use the official uh SDK by
Facebook for certain program language
yeah yeah well I was going to say
another one that we've seen is like
you'll create an account then link your
Facebook account to it and you can
change your email on the on the
vulnerable site and then you just log in
with the same Facebook account and it's
tied to maybe that's what you were just
saying but it's tied to the account ID
and so there's like two separate account
references that get linked together here
and it doesn't really matter what what
is on your Facebook account as long as
it's
valid yeah so I guess we've got that you
mentioned a vul story and then we got we
got on a little on a little a little
tangent there do you want to go back to
that one okay so this one uh it's a
combination of uh lot of stuff uh post
message and uh also uh cryp
cryptographic uh secure uh functions and
not secure functions in the client sit
yeah lock up yeah yeah so basically the
Facebook has uh uh this uh uh messenger
chat plugin uh it's included in the
JavaScript SDK in uh client in uh fa
with Facebook so basically when you uh
when you uh use the plugin it would just
pop up a sh chat uh and you can chat
with that page uh in uh Facebook so
actually Facebook use that plug-in in
their own website in an endpoint like
facebook.com gosm marketing something
like that so
um it loads the plug-in and uh that
plug-in uh at some point it has a do xss
but to reach that uh to reach the point
to exploit the do xss uh that's the hard
part uh that will uh work to uh we try
to do uh so uh the communication between
the iframe iframe the holding the
plug-in the this chat plugin and the
main page facebook.com/ gos they are
communicating and they're doing like uh
some kind of uh check uh the check is
um a call back for for example if you uh
have a post message from the iframe to
the parent uh it should uh have like uh
an ID a certain ID which is uh let's say
uh random stuff and if it's true uh it
would uh allow it to call many functions
and where thex happens we see this quite
this is a pretty common thing with with
post messages where there's like a a you
know some sort of randomiz or some sort
of and then that is tied to a specific
Handler or set of handlers that that
often see that yeah I've seen this on
mobile as well actually with like
JavaScript Bridges going between the web
View and the the same same exact thing
yeah so tell tell us how you broke
it yeah so basically uh this uh I went
to the part where how this ID is
generated and it was generated with
math. random function uh this function
is not uh cryptographically secure like
uh uh what that means uh uh the Pudo
pseudo random
generator uh if you can leak four or
five values of math. random you can
reverse to find the seed and from that
seed You can predict the next value for
of that random uh number so what uh my
objective was to leak the like three or
five math do random values of that page
and from there I can predict the next
one or I can reverse and find the you
know the call back uh uh ID for uh the
to use for communication and to Le that
uh math do random IDs they actually uh
named the iframe you know window. name
so they use the same function they use
to generate the call back IDs they use
it to generate the window do name
interesting so now if I can if I'm able
to leak window. name of an i frame I can
uh if I can leak it four or five times
without refreshing the page because that
would set the seed that's what I was
going to say because I literally have
done the same bug and actually shout out
to Donut My Man donut uh because uh he
he's done a talk on this and I I pinged
him I was like hey I read your talk I
still don't understand any of it you
know on the insecure you know sud random
stuff and then he kind of walked me
through it and we we figured out in my
specific scenario it wasn't exploitable
but it sounds like you found a way to
actually leak some of the seeds without
refreshing it which is a this is once
again is this gadget after Gadget after
Gadget chained together yeah to create
this so yeah continue so the
facebook.com page uh in Mobile like uh
this is related to mobile all right so
in Mobile they returned like uh uh they
return earned XF frame options with
allow from so allow from is debated
basically and it's ignored in Mobile and
even in desktop version uh so uh
basically that page can be
iframed okay I'm sorry so facebook.com X
x-frame options and then there's allow
from and then it specifies a domain and
that's depreciated so it just ignores it
yeah interesting that's for any of you
Recon people out there that'd be a good
thing to hit like Mass search for to see
where there could be this configuration
where they're thinking they've got a
secure x-frame conf configuration but
they don't very interesting I'm sorry
continue yeah so that page facebook.com/
goals that page that load the if frame
with the plugin now is I'm if frameable
so I can if frame it in my website in
Mobile so when I iframe it uh so
attacker.com can access the inner iframe
of course and can read the
name of the if frame so I can leak like
uh one value of M rondom because I can
uh read the ifame name which is like
uses uh was generated based on math. R
wow so after this is nuts yeah so after
that uh I'll just uh send another uh so
the way to not refresh the page to uh to
maintain the same uh browsing session so
uh they had like
other uh functions or that you can
access without having that uh certain
callback ID or certain that ID uh one
allowed you to refresh the if frame or
to uh try to create the Plug-In or
refresh the plugin so each time you it
refresh the plugin it generated a new uh
window. name and generated absolutely
ridiculous when it works out like that
this is nuts I
line so now if you leak five even if
they're separated for example you have a
math do random value then one that you
couldn't leak then one that you could
leak so even if they separated by one or
two uh you can actually uh find the seed
so wow yeah so uh I found the seed I uh
calculated the next Ma trandom and uh
got the ID used the ID to uh exploit the
do xss yeah it's so cool cuz this is
like almost a CTF challenge I I I feel
like I haven't even thought about like
math. random in since like I did ctfs
you know like um and it's so interesting
I didn't realize that Java Script math.
random was vulnerable to that as well
yeah it's been for years wow it's been
known too if only somebody could fix it
yeah I know they fixed it they have like
uh now with secure crypto yeah they have
it but
but it's Bassa random is still
vulnerable it's still vulnerable but
it's faster so the secure random class
there's like a secure random class right
is that what you mean like the two
separate yeah so math random is uh
vulnerable to these type of attacks but
they have like a safe one uh in
JavaScript
crypto yeah I think it's crypto API or
something it's totally safe wow well a
lot of people still using math. random
so definitely definitely an interesting
thing there and then that whole concept
of you know graphing all these random
you know these points that are in the
random generator function and then
generating the seeds off of it really
cool um I loved that research by donut
and uh and others as well so um very
cool there
so I wanted to kind of so that was that
was a cool a mobile piece as well which
is great I wanted to see that um and I
kind of want to go back to what you
mentioned earlier you said a lot of
things make the alarms go off you know
in the head and that was one of the
questions I had here and so here are
some things that I could kind of come up
with off the top of my head um you know
a flows any sort of domain handoff of
information post messages cookie Bridges
etc those are all things that kind of
make my my brain kind of go whoa whoa
wait a second uh I think I should be
paying more attention to uh hash changes
from this conversation that we've had I
I'll be paying more attention to that in
the future um can you think of any other
things off the I know I'm putting you on
the spot but um can you think of any
other things off the top of your head
that sort of get the the alarms sounding
in in your brain yeah so uh sometimes
like uh not a lot of people would look
in uh uh Dome generated HTML for example
uh if you have like GS code that would
create an i frame and the iframe uh
source is Set uh from uh unnown unnown
source so we have a sync like many SS
they're not known to people like for
example if you set the action of a form
to JavaScript your scheme it's an xss if
you set the iframe source to uh
JavaScript OS scheme it's an xss so
sometimes I just focus on things that
uh let's say uh like using Create
element doc I create element and then
you kind of see and sort like direct
inner HTML set or something like that
interesting interesting yeah inner HTML
is one of the things I always search for
obviously but I don't always search for
yeah create create element that's that's
smart and then specifically for these
specific types we've got you've got
Source you or I'm sorry you've got
script you've got iframe you've got uh
what what are some of the other ones
form form form yeah form action setting
action to and then setting action that's
good would you say you start more at
sources or
sinks so uh yeah I wanted to ask this
too question so uh most of the time I
start with sources yeah but my man give
give me some right here team sources
let's go yeah yeah but in I'm all about
the doam hunting I need a sink get out
of here Joel get out of here yeah
because even if you find a vulnerable
sink you have to trace it back and you
do but with Source it's like it's
obvious where the going and and I think
Source related stuff also lends itself
to gadget hunting you know like like
even if you don't have sync even if it
doesn't result in an actionable
vulnerability you can do stuff you know
and that's what I'm all about I think I
get a hold on just a second sir so you
mean the 50 unexploitable bugs that I've
been documenting are useless shut up
shut up Joel hold on no you know the the
just I'm all about knowing what I can do
with the application as an hacker right
I want to know every place every
location where I can affect the app you
know and and I think hunting from
sources really helps you understand
holistically what an attacker is capable
of doing in the app even if it's
something benign you know like creating
an element on the page that that you
have no control over right but it
inflates page size or you know who knows
maybe it's some random cookie gets sent
and you can you know and and it's a
randomly generated uh cookie key and
then you can inflate the the cookie size
and cause client side Doss or something
like that and then use that in a
different bug so with sources uh you
always end up with something yeah
exactly something that's worth I'm going
to clip that I'm going to clip I'm
getting indirectly roasted out here this
is SC forward a little
bit no that's great man I I'm glad to
hear you say that as well sources
sometimes but uh sometimes like uh I'd
look for s that uh yeah I look for SS uh
before sources all right in certain
condition Let's ignore that part anyway
youf I've got some other questions for
you no no no I'm sorry go ahead you do
look for sinks yeah yeah yeah so like I
said if I know that page uh uh is
setting if frame is creating an element
if frame or form or something and I'm
sure like uh I'm sure like they're using
uh they have a source that I control or
something I just straight look for syns
because I'm sure that uh eventually
they'll use my source or yeah because I
guaranteed The Source parts so now I'm
looking because you know what what type
of stuff you're looking for like for
example with like the iframe stuff
you're looking for changing the HF
you're looking for changing the URL or
the window location through JavaScript
like so you're going to Target a sync
instead of looking for an entrance got
it yeah I'm I'm looking at my notes here
and we sort of covered a little bit this
already but I'll I'll Repose the
question which is you know so similar to
an ooth code being sent to any path on
the thing like if you can control the
path with the redirect URL right um what
are some other things that you've seen
since you specialize in account takeover
what are some other things that you've
seen that result in account takeover and
what I've learned from you already today
is leaking location.href is is pivotal
um and so I assume that's one of them
yeah yeah so also self access
basically having self accss you can leak
the O uh token
uh uh most scenarios you can do it so uh
for me in some targets self accesss is
directly an ATO does it have to have a
csrf to update like to trigger the self
xss because I assume your attack
basically like attacker loads page
updates an xss to themselves which then
triggers your attack or like you're
talking about like Trigg triggering the
self access via cesf login and then you
have to have a csrf so basically that's
why it's called self xss uh so you self
xss yourself in a certain session in the
victim browser to actually uh uh trigger
that xss in the that pren context from
that origin right and all of that to
actually for example access an open it
page from the previous session that uh
to read the window I I've used that
before right where you have a um where
you have a page that's already open and
then you establish a you know a self
exsess and then you go back up and reach
over and grab it and bring it back in
that's interesting it would be more
interesting if we could figure out how
to actively have control of the victim
session in a different Tab and I was
thinking about this the other day and I
was wondering whether it's possible to
manipulate same site cookie policies to
create create two separate sessions in
inside the browser and so like say for
example I've got my attacker control
page that's got an frame right that if
frame is not a top level navigation so
uh it's not going to be have cookies
sent to it right and then within that
within that if frame I I log in myself
right trigger the xss reach back through
the parent and over to the opener tab
which I've now redirected to the other
site the victim site and that site still
has the session open of the victim but
it's an isolated cookie session have you
seen anything like this before do you
think that would work or is am I missing
something here I'm not sure because yeah
because if you said the cookie is set
I'm not sure it would be set in that
context uh we'll we'll look it up at I I
tried to look this up the other day and
I actually did an experiment on my own
little website with various Origins and
I don't think that cookie is set on that
other tab which makes me think that
those cookies are still there's like
some sort of different context and I'm
sure what's going to
happen it's probably like some sort of
cookie store cuz like on Chrome for
example if you open the application tab
you have like cookies that are
associated with that application quote
unquote um and it could be that it's
basically just not reloaded from the
like it has to load it from the browser
from the cookie store in order to have
it associated with it yeah that that's
what I'm thinking I think that could be
a really and I'm sure what's G to happen
is after this episode airs someone's
going to be like hey Justin here's the
solution to this which I love so please
continue to do that people like this is
this is one of the things I love the
most about podcasting is I get free free
research from people that just send me
the answers to the things I want to know
um but it's very interesting and I wish
I had the answer off the top of my head
I didn't I got pulled away that day but
um I think that would be really
interesting right because then you know
you would actually just be able to
control that session with the other
cookies and you that would be a new way
to kind of execute self X assess but who
knows if it'll actually work sometimes
like you don't actually need all of that
so for for example you established a
certain uh state in that page just leave
it like that and do start do the all
like log out csrf login csrf and
everything and just uh come back after
all of that and exploit that page
because it won't reload unless they have
like uh uh client site code that would
uh for example if it detects the cookie
changes if it detects uh log out state
it would refresh unless they do that uh
you're safe so just keep it waiting and
do the self accesss and come back that
yeah that's one of the one of the
biggest arguments I think for putting
CES protection around login and log out
mechanisms is that any self xss can be
really uh badly exploited you know in a
situation like that if you have both of
those gadgets in place for login and log
out C serf and this is another um sort
of con of using centralized logged
system so because if you've got the
cookies isolated to a specific domain
and then you know I I hit login. you
know whatever.com and that that still
has its session live and I can relog in
you know if they don't fully log out the
person out um then that can also result
in some some bad stuff uh and as well as
um social media logins and that sort of
thing also some things like for example
you have a self accss let's say uh in
facebook.com but uh because Facebook
meta have like this centralized uh like
uh like uh let's say a platform for
example uh they allow some things uh to
be happen to happen from workplace.com
accessing facebook.com facebook.com so
if you find the self access in
facebook.com uh you'll just Target
directly workplace user you'll just
Target an Instagram user because they
have like there these chain these these
Bridges bridges some kind of bridges
that's a great that's a great point and
and one of the things I've mentioned
mention to my my mes recently is like
anytime you see any sort of domain
bridging yeah you've got to fully Deep
dive that and and we see that you know
um let's just say at plenty of live
hacking events that we've been involved
in there's been issues with that and uh
and so uh it's definitely definitely a
uh a great spot to continue to look for
vulnerabilities um all right so let
let's uh let's move a little bit here
to um well I've got a couple directions
we could go here we could go and talk
about um window frame relationships uh
window. opener window window. parent
that sort of thing and uh sort of
different ways to establish references
to Windows um or we could go the message
Port route I don't know let let me just
ask this have you done anything with
message ports um inside of post message
related I once found an at with the
message port and message Channel okay
nice Yeah so basically message message
Port is like uh a port uh you can use to
communicate uh instead of it's
eventually it uses post message but uh
initially you set you create a new
message channel uh message channel has
two ports uh you send with post message
uh to uh the the target page you want to
talk with uh and you include the message
Port one of the message ports from that
message Channel okay interesting so you
and I I found a a message Port bug
before but it was very rudimentary so I
didn't actually have to fully understand
the the message Port functionality so
are you able to send the message Port
reference yeah cross origin yeah cross
origin you send it in post message and
it can only read once or uh that
particular message Port it can only be
read once by so you can't like for
example save the reference
or so it can be consumed one uh
once okay interesting okay so uh
basically why they why they do that so
they establish let's say uh attacker uh
facebook.com want wants to communicate
with a certain domain and they don't
want to every time check the origin
check everything do the sour check they
do it once and uh they do all the checks
and if all the checks are good they
share with them the message Port now
that new message channel is totally safe
we can trust each other we don't need to
uh
do yeah lovely okay is there any catches
to that you know yeah so basically if
you can leak that message board that
have the the communication uh without
Security checks if you can leak it
basically you can uh do a lot of stuff
is the message Port reference just like
a string or H how does it how do you
like pass it yeah so it can be passed in
uh ports in ports in post message so
post message allowed you to share uh
message ports or object uh message Port
interesting so I feel like there must be
some way to like fetch it by name in the
underlying apis right like somehow the
browser is able to fetch a message Port
object off of that name so that it can
communicate with it right somehow yeah
yeah no actually it us it that reference
of message port to uh to just make a new
object and then it just no no to to send
a message oh it's just it's an yeah so
in memory they have like because uh two
of them they they they have different
origin so they have like some kind of uh
maybe uh like memory in memory they uh
both can access the same buffer I guess
but uh uh this this is so when you said
that I'm like what what is this I'm
looking at the post message ndn right
now okay it and it says or mdn it says
there's an option for post message to
take three parameters message Target
origin and then transfer transfer yeah
for uh transferable objects and I've
never even I've never so clonable
objects so for example Rex can be shared
uh we're going to make a new we're going
to have a new a new session now where we
quiz Yousef on mdn documentation and see
if he can recite it word for word yeah
yeah Contin a lot of objects can be
shared but
uh uh not like uh so let's see there's
there's um there's array buffer message
Port readable stream writable stream
transfer stream uh web transport receive
stream that's interesting web transfer
send stream audio data image bit map
video frame frame offscreen canvas and
RTC data Channel yeah very interesting
and and so do these when these are
transferred I wonder how it actually is
that a part of that e object that you
that you get when you do so they they
maintain the same object prototype they
uh that's why it's not actually
interesting really because you can like
change for example uh uh the object uh
you can add for example something it
shares the data of course but it doesn't
change the Prototype ah okay so because
sometimes like
you I found a situation where uh it
there is a check if it's a string and
after that they'll do something treat it
as an object uh okay so maybe if we can
manipulate the man manipulate the
Prototype uh so it's a string but it
contains let's say uh uh a key called
save equals something sure so you can do
that with with the transfer the post
message transfer so it maintains the
same prototype of that object there's a
lot of really interesting information in
this doc yeah so there is actually a
nice trick there so uh C Target origin
so uh a lot of people assume that uh it
needs to be string but actually it can
be an object uh with a key Target origin
and uh
value equals
to the actual origin this uh you can use
it to bypass a lot of checks string
checks yeah if at the time the event is
scheduled to dispatch the scheme host
name report of the Windows document does
not match the provided Target origin it
will not be dispatched only all three
match will be
dispatched dude that yeah this is really
interesting huh I did not know that so
you can provide it with an object there
that will
because then it so look I'm sorry you've
probably got it in your head for those
of you that are are listening not
watching I'm sorry we're looking at the
mdn but look see the the post message
has two has two um uh sort of what's
what's the technical term for that it's
like overloading
function yeah function overloading um
there one of them is message options and
one of them is message Target or origin
the one that we normally see is message
Target origin with which is the string
but there's also so the one with options
where you can specify Target origin and
also specify transfer objects as well
inside of that options very interesting
so if you have the ability to affect the
second parameter directly of a post
message request then you can specify a
Target origin key inside of that object
yeah yeah so sometimes like they'll
check the target origin as a string and
for example if it's an object they'll
ignore it or I'm not sure so you can
bypass the first check and the said
Target origin to The Domain you want oh
crazy I'm clapping into the and and
again this transferable object thing we
we'll put a link in the description but
the behavior of this like I was just
reading through how it how it explains
how this works and it's it's very
similar to what you said where it's like
when you transfer an object it literally
moves the
memory the block of memory to a
different ownership and depending on the
type of object like it says here for
example when an array buffer is
transferred the memory resource that it
points to is literally moved instead of
copying the data other objects are
transferred by copying the associated
resources and deleting the old one so
yeah they actually had like uh you know
now they have site isolation but they
had like the possibility to share uh to
have the shared buffer shared using post
message and the two sites will uh for
example if you make change to that
buffer it would be Chang in the other
one so that time uh
so this I actually used but it didn't
succeed so let's you share shared buffer
and
uh you keep it as it is for example with
origin checks with everything when you
reach the point where uh for example uh
it would uh make a post message to me
with that origin I Just sh change the
shared buffer and it would be Chang in
that uh R condition yeah basically race
conditioning that's so interesting I I I
need to look dude I'm telling you man
post message is the [__] I love post
message um that that's great and and so
the other thing that we had you know
from before was talking about window
relationship window frame relationships
okay so I'm I'm just going to kind of
talk through a couple of those we've got
the window. opener right that's the tab
that's opened the current page the
window. parent that's going to be your
your um if frames parent um and then
you've got some other things as well you
know you can Traverse into different
frames by using a specific window
reference and then do frames and that
will include all the frames associated
with that page and then um but I'm a
little bit confused because I I thought
I did something recently and and it
didn't work where I had a child page
that did a window do open MH is that
populated into the window frames or does
it need to have a specific reference do
you know
off the top of your head on whether how
you can get a reference to let's say I I
open up a page right okay you need to
keep the reference in a variable you
can't access it directly like yeah yeah
so if I control the page yes but if the
if it's a different origin so I pop open
a page that page pops open another page
um there's no way I can get a reference
to that third page oh it's impossible
it's impossible ah dude that's so that's
so frustrating I know that there is
something that I read
by name by yeah okay so have you ever
done anything with that I don't I I
couldn't get it to work properly and we
we talked about it on the podcast one
time but I don't remember whether we
actually got it to work ever uh this
will work if the popup window was open
from a different frame on the same
domain same domain yeah on Modern
Brothers this will even work at the
window is yes it also says being in the
I'm just I'm In My Own Zone in modern
browsers uh this will even work if the
window has been opened from a different
frame on a different domain but this can
cause some strange behavior in Internet
Explorer specifically yeah so maybe
that's worth looking into but uh that
that is super interesting so by window
name you can basically uh not window uh
like uh when you set window. open you
set the name of the the open window
later when uh let's say uh
uh yeah it's actually call it again it
just yeah yeah I wonder if I can store a
frame reference so for example I have a
attacker page attacker page opens up
another attacker page frame right that
page opens up another frame with window
with a window. open specifying the name
parameter then this guy gets a reference
to that one because this is all same
origin at this point yeah you can have
then this guy redirects away I still
have a reference to that that I'm sorry
this is terrible for any of you
listening on the actual podcast because
I've got my hand and I'm just waving it
you know in the air um so let me try let
me try one more time I'm sorry youf so
I've got an attacker controlled page
that opens another page and then so this
is page number two page number two opens
up a new tab with and these are all same
origin at this point with with window.
name uh or window. open specifying the
name parameter and then the second page
transfers away but you're still able to
reference that third page from the first
page yeah I don't think it's possible
you don't think so yeah I don't think so
because the
middle page is low so unless you keep
the reference uh to a variable right
that's kind I was thinking I if we can
reference if we can get a reference to
it and then you can actually access yeah
cuz like why can't you open a new tab
store that as a reference in memory with
it like a name to tab that you know is
going to be reused and then say your
your attacker or sorry the website
you're attacking the victim site does a
window. open with the same window name
you still have a reference to that
because you controlled it originally and
it's going to update
that existing window to the new URL
right so I have no idea man this is this
is definitely something I'd like to see
more research on the window. name or the
window
name sometimes you know the the ey frame
can be the opener of the parent window
yeah there are some tricks that you can
do yeah whoa whoa hold hold up hold up
hold up say that one more time the the
what the I frame uh now is the opener of
the parent window so the when you you
look in opener in parent you'll find the
if frame as an
opener yeah but this is notf how yeah so
uh that doesn't make any sense it makes
it makes so
uh I don't remember the details but it's
possible wow dude we got but you it's
not like something big that you can use
unless that there are some conditions
for an attack to happen uh like that
partic in a particular way so in that
case uh you can uh you can wow yeah dude
that's crazy man I I I've definitely
want to do some more research into this
and kind of so this there's this article
that we've referenced a couple times on
the podcast it's called every known way
to get references to Windows in
JavaScript we we'll we'll link it in the
description for this episode but it does
a pretty good job I don't think it's
every every single way so do do you know
about the opener policy like uh no talk
to me about it yeah so uh now with the
browser you can control if uh you want
to keep the reference to the opener or
not or ah I have seen this yes and and
you can do it in the um is this
something you do in the metat tag or is
it a part of
the metadata or in the headers right
okay yeah and headers yeah yeah I guess
in the headers yeah yeah cross origin
oper policy Coupe uh oh Coupe yeah yeah
yeah okay okay that's right so that
limited some of the uh client side
attacks so
Visa
Texs yeah how how are you going about
finding out about new stuff because
there's like I mean the browser space
especially is changing a lot but even
just separate from that like the
programs that you hack on a lot how are
you finding new features are you just
sort of like watching their blog or how
do how do you look for new stuff to hack
on on those same targets and also like
stay up to date about like browser level
stuff at the same time yeah so with
browsers it's basically they have like
always discussions about uh like uh how
to uh fix this how to um so they're
always discussing stuff and I always uh
keep looking into the into them and uh
I'll check origin trials for new
features in browsers and uh go read
about them uh with targets uh it's about
Recon so you have uh scripts in the
background checking javascripts file is
downloading them and uh trying to find a
new code new stuff and uh if it's found
uh I just start working on it yeah so
actually that's a perfect transition I I
wanted to talk about Recon so I think
you have a JavaScript monitoring sort of
system that you've got right so can you
talk a little bit about that and how
that works and and sort of how that
plays into what we just talked about
Yeah so basically uh let's uh uh for
example Facebook uh they have like an
inpoint that would
download react modules or return
javascrip files that include that module
so basically what I do u i just uh keep
downloading JavaScript files keep
collecting module names uh uh after that
uh query that endpoint for more
JavaScript files and keep the loop on
and uh also scraping Pages like uh in
Facebook for uh new module names and
after that download the JavaScript files
so it's about collecting as much as
possible of so it seems like so for me
just from a naive perspective I'm
looking at I'm looking at these whole
JavaScript sort of packages that they
have in a specific application as a
holistic entity and as as individual you
know or not as individual you know
modules and stuff like that inside um
and and I think I know of some hackers
that that do it a little bit more
granular okay okay this piece you know
of code is a part of this library or
this module which is a part of this
whole thing that's web packed into this
you know minified garbage that we all
have to read um so I assume you know
Facebook gives you this nice end point
where you download the modules
individually but how do you do you take
that same approach when you're looking
at different targets where it's like I'm
separating out okay this modules a piece
of this and how do you parse this minifi
JavaScript to to break apart all these
different modules and packages and stuff
like that yeah so with other targets
like Facebook is too nice to have like
the module names uh with the other
targets it's like offis cated the mod
name is random sometimes it's just uh an
ID or numbers yeah so that actually
we're going to come back to I'll let you
finish but we I do want to come back to
webpack Lazy loaded things where they've
got the you know one two3 colon has. JS
whatever but anyway continue yeah yeah
yeah so uh I'll just uh focus on not the
the actual contain of the function I'll
just uh like let's say I'll give it a
hash like that uh particular function uh
with with what it's doing now or it's
contained now even if character is
changed let's say variable name a b c
like that doesn't matter uh and uh I'll
give it a hash and that hash reference
uh to that particular function now I'll
just keep monitoring if that function
was changed is this minified code yes oh
interesting so you're you're
you're if I understood it correctly
you're you're taking a specific function
you're hashing in so are you doing like
as trees and like breaking down the
whole code
structure yeah and two functions and
dude yeah but uh it's not perfect but it
keeps me like with all the like the
hundreds of function and all of that uh
I just keep uh some kind of reference
that this function is actually may be
this function from a old version of that
package so that way I can like uh
minimize the like yeah false positives I
can look for new functions a new code do
you have an elegant way of dealing with
like variable names because I imagine if
you hash like a web packed function and
then the next version it's got different
variable names but it might be the same
function yeah it depends on the target
so sometimes I'll just uh detect that uh
uh they'll use uh single characters or
for example uh uh I'll uh the uh the
arguments would be a bcde e f so that's
uh fixed but in
the uh actual function itself they'll
use sometimes random uh uh characters so
I'll have like different versions and uh
different hash for different uh if this
was a if this was B if this was uh C got
it so it's it's not perfect but it's
just for comparison like to find like uh
after downloading uh this month's uh
version uh
this particular has yeah is it just to
try and reduce that attack service down
something usable yeah and okay so then
do you do any of the hot AI stuff with
it as well like do you run it through
chat GPT or anything like that or is it
is it just Yousef GPT like no no I use
uh sometimes chat gbt to just like clear
the code like
uh okay can you uh can you understand
what's happening here just uh not SP the
B but just uh like as code uh with chat
gbt currently I only use it uh let's say
as a programmer not as a security from a
security perspective so as a programmer
just CLE clarify this codes clarify uh
the names variable names make a sense of
them and that's it and after that I'll
just do the security checks I I want to
go back to that hashing thing you
mentioned so are you using a to to parse
out like because JavaScript has like
there's just like 15 bajillion ways to
Define functions and like you know
there's just a mess of syntax that you
have to do so are you using Rex for this
are you using you know syntax parsing
are you doing how are you doing this so
the only reason I'm doing this for
example when uh the first thing uh I do
after downloading the package is uh
break it on functions or uh
parts so now uh with the new version I
have of that package I want to make sure
that this function uh is not like uh new
I already checked it it's uh so I
already have in the previous version uh
uh hashes of that function with like
even with the conditions that that
variable was changed to G that variable
name was changed so if uh I do check of
that uh of the of the function in the
new package it's hash I'll check it in
the previous ones if it's just found
I'll just remove that function and focus
on the new how are you extracting the
functions
though uh it's like um minifi and uh
like uh with the grip brakes and all
yeah so it's uh doing a regular
Expressions yeah yeah wow that's that's
a lot man there there's there's some
technology that I've been using um which
I think do you know what it stands for
off the top of your head Joel AB syntax
tree yeah so I keep on wanting to say
trees okay what abst abstract syntax
tree so it should just
be don't don't abstract syntax trees um
essentially what it does and this is how
um uh J loose the tool that Tom Nom Nom
released uh deals with this and
essentially what it does is it allows
you to par the grammar of of those
specific spefic um code base that you're
dealing with so I've done some
automation with this with uh with PHP
and you can also do this with JS where
it will go through and say okay this is
a function here's give me all function
definitions and it'll query that whole
code block for any function definitions
yeah it's essentially it's a
programmatic way of parsing code right
so it's a j like JavaScript has these
built-in libraries that you give it a
chunk of JavaScript code and it will
return an object that you can then say
uh you know what what's the first
variable definition
and if so what's on the left side what's
on the right side variable name value
and what's what's the name of this
function what line is it at how big is
it and it it will do all of that in like
a a codified way so it's a lot more
strict in terms of like it has to be
valid JavaScript code it has to be able
to validly parse it and understand it
for it to get there which you should be
able to um but it's yeah I like that
approach more like Rex I I would always
be worried that i' be missing stuff
probably that's that's yeah but uh well
you you know what you're looking for
specifically because yeah because I have
certain like let's say code or rejects
for this target for this target so uh I
spent some times like with each Target
uh to basically have the Ricon right and
after that I just forget it this is
exactly what we've been talking about is
like and I've actually spoken with some
people in the um in the critical
thinking Community about building this
and I I kind of got about halfway
through it myself and I haven't swung
back around to it but essentially
building instead of building a JS
monitoring tool building a JS monitoring
framework because at the end of the day
all of these scripts should be custom
because for each Target they're going to
have a different you know uh way that
they're doing everything and you know a
different way of getting the files and
then you got to you know un laaz load
them and then load them all in and then
JS beautify them and then everything all
the formats are different so really for
each Target you've got individual things
you should be looking at differently and
so I think that what should do is build
a python package that makes monitoring
these things a little bit easier and say
okay you know here's an HTML page grab
this specific script tag okay now you've
got the script tag great we've got an
automatic um you know da loader that
that you know runs node on the inside
and just you know dumps out all the
values for these lazy loaded files and
stuff like that um and then build a
library surrounding that and then we use
that library to create specific
automation for specific um
uh
targets using these sort of tools and it
seems like that's what you've done yeah
but uh in uh it's for me it's still a
tool not framework like I do yeah yeah
it's not do you just run it once and it
does everything at once or do you have
different sorry do
you I imagine like I have just like a
microphone attached to me at all times
um so do you do you run it just like one
and done and it does everything at once
or do you have different no but I have
to set it up I need to do some manual
work uh at first and after that per
Target per Target yeah and after that
set a few things uh and keep it working
yeah very cool it kind of reminds me of
um there's a couple different Source map
uh JavaScript Source map unpacking tools
that are like this CU Source map also it
can be a little bit different per you
know how it's how it's deployed or
whatever and so sometimes you need to
pull it from a different like index on
in an array or something like index one
instead of index zero and one of the
tools that I've used is is it
specifically allows you to configure
like I want it from this path on the and
it'll specifically do that I think
something like that plus what Justin was
talking about would be a good approach
where you could say say like for this
target the thing I'm looking for is here
and then you just feed it a blob and it
just parses it pulls it out and then you
can just run that every single time
until it changes um yeah I like that
idea yeah and I I'll mentioned this I
haven't played around with this tool yet
but somebody in the critical thinkers uh
the premium chat for uh for our our
Discord um released this or posted this
in here the other day it's uh github.com
uh mid xnet mapper plus it seems like a
it says an advanced Source map extractor
based on a headless browser and this is
something that I thought about doing for
a while using headless browser to
actually do that Source map abstraction
um uh easier be nice yeah yeah and so
I'm GNA I'm definitely going to check
this out after this they they dumped it
on me right as I was about to go and do
uh a live hacking event so I haven't had
the chance to check it out yet but I
think there's a lot of innovation that
could be done in the source map space
and obviously you've got um I won't say
mine is the most Innovative one yeah
because yeah it's basic but uh because I
I'm just looking for certain stuff so
after all it's code uh if I detect a
pattern in the in the code I just uh I
don't need to fully understand it or
reverse engineer it or yeah no and I
think that that shows that shows though
that shows that you know what you're
looking for which I think is is very
good just just one second jool and then
um but so the The webpack Lazy loading
piece obviously we've got tools like um
jce loose and um JS weasel that are kind
of addressing this as well um have you
do have your
own I guess piece of technology to go
through and and address those sort of
lazy loaded pieces where it's like you
know 1 two 3 4 colon hash and then it's
dynamically creating that that JS file
do you know what I'm talking about or is
it a little too abstract actually I
didn't like uh like with the targets I
work on I don't usually see uh they
don't have that very often okay it's uh
it's too complicated unfortunate I mean
lazy load of JavaScript is so annoying
to hack on um Let me let me just do this
though Joel I'm not even sure if you saw
because we've been uh you know kneep in
the live hacking event but I just
released to the um to the to the
critical thinkers Discord the premium
channel
a new so I'll share this with you to
youf I I um I and you'll have access to
it after this anyway because we give all
the speakers access to the exclusive
content but um the for I've been trying
to solve this problem of like how do I
programmatically extract lazy loaded
JavaScript for a while right and and
it's these functions that look like this
I I'll turn it around you can see it on
the left hand side but it's uh it's
these you know these numbers right here
on the side and then the hash and then
it automatically generates it so for a
while the first version of the script
that I did was using these crazy rejects
to like parse out the number and the
correlating the name in the hash and the
number and the hash and it was just a
whole cluster right and then I realized
oh [__] the function that has this
defined in in the JavaScript is actually
a function designed to dynamically
generate yeah you don't do the name so
just all I had to do was copy the
function okay you know put it in my
script run eval and then pass every
number that I see and it just
automatically generates yeah yeah you
you don't have to worry about that yeah
exactly exactly and so um so now we've
got a very easy way to extract that um
using node uh and you know obviously in
the browser that they're only going to
load the things that they need
dynamically um but when we were doing
recon we want to have every access to
every single JS file so I released that
script to the uh to the critical
thinkers um we'll uh we'll we'll leave
it as a as a uh as a task to the to the
non-critical thinking listeners um to go
ahead and build that yourself uh but
it's been very helpful for me with with
uh Recon an analysis and I think it
would be for other people as well um one
other question that I had here and then
we'll kind of go into a little bit more
of hacking methodology stuff uh as we
close is how do you deal
with I guess how do you think about
client side routing in an application
that you're looking at like do you often
go through there and try to enumerate
all of the client side routes that are
associated with a an application um and
do you have
any uh tips and tricks you use for this
with various Frameworks or is it mostly
just going in there reading the code
putting in the time to understand where
all those client side routes are defined
yeah yeah so I I initially uh try to
understand how they Define routes and
everything after that that's a pretty
high priority for you in the beginning
or uh yeah at some point not in the
beginning but at some point I try to
find routes and uh CLI side routes of
course and uh uh after that uh I just uh
like extract all the list and review it
my so it's mainly a manual uh man mainly
a manual process yeah that that's
something that I'd also like to see some
innovation in the space and I always
like to mention this on the podcast
because somebody's going to get some
Joel like person out there is going to
get triggered and have to go write this
tool that is like yeah um you know like
react or you know all of these different
Frameworks have their own way of
defining these client side routes and I
think it'd be really cool to just kind
of um have some sort of browser Plugin
or some sort of tool that would show me
exactly what code is being executed when
I I go to this specific route and for
this event I can talk about it you know
for this event um you know there's
there's this you you for one of the
targets you visit a route and then it's
got like this whole weird stretch of
JavaScript and then instantiates a class
so the first thing that really runs is
like the Constructor of this class
associated with that specific route um
and so you know if that's a common thing
it'd be really cool to be able to link
it to that class and would help with
enumerating all these rather than having
to set break points and then work back
so that's what I do is that what you do
as well yeah so I have to it's like uh
to some point it's uh complicated uh you
have to find like the first uh uh first
lead and after that follow it to
understand how it works and uh you do it
with the single route and after that you
can do it to uh yeah automate it with
other routes yeah a lot a lot of it
sounds like sort of that that
calibration that you're talking about
where when you're starting on a new
Target like
identifying what are the patterns how
how do they structure stuff what do
their routes look like what do client
side routes look like um I noticed that
a lot in Mobile as well actually because
mobile again lots of aisc same looking
for patterns so you mentioned um in your
your bug Bounty reports explained
interview that you wanted to do more
like you know mobile stuff and less web
have you been doing that yeah so I won't
say I did more mobile than web but right
so it was like uh couple of so I I've
been working with uh on o for uh like uh
for the p uh past few years years and I
wanted to know how mobile handles that
so yeah it was uh it was a research
about like uh let's say uh you want to
to connect to uh in a company using
Facebook uh in Mobile and how that is
handled how the communication between
that company uh application with the
Facebook application uh how the they
start the in intent with the parameters
Facebook shake shs these parameters and
make the O call uh so uh I I did a
research with on Facebook uh like loging
in with Facebook on mobile and uh I
found like a couple or three bags there
awesome how like uh they can verify how
the application that requested the O's
token of uh let's say app ID equals one
yeah how we we can verify that
application have has the right to uh
access or to read that oath uh they did
some like Android app signing and all of
that but uh at certain uh Point uh they
failed to uh it's like rear condition
they failed to uh have like uh uh to
pass the uh the signature in the oath
request or the signed like Android uh
key or something yeah they passed they
uh they fail to pass it and uh with that
if in the server side if it receives a
null uh key uh it would just return the
oath like it would be successful and uh
yeah yeah but
uh uh it's not like uh automatic you
need to allow for example let's say uh
you're browsing any app yep and uh a
popup will show which app do you want to
open this in no no uh popup will show do
you authorize Instagram oh wow yeah do
you authorize Instagram uh application
to access your uh your account let's say
okay uh you need to confirm but when you
confirm you're not confirming the
sharing of the oath token with the anag
app but with the attacker app I see so
when you do that um when you're looking
at these stuff are you mainly looking at
like The Meta owned apps are you looking
at other apps that Implement like
Facebook login for example through ooth
yeah because even other apps would use
the SDK by Facebook so it doesn't matter
I just focus on the main Facebook app
and the SDK because they probably use
the same yeah yeah they use their own
SDK yeah and another back I found is uh
like uh race condition uh I'm not sure
it's uh zero day in uh it's not uh so
they have JavaScript bridge in web view
uh where you can uh so they predefine
some JavaScript functions that uh uh you
can call from uh let's say target.com
page uh in Facebook web View and
target.com page can
uh uh like have the O uh uh token uh uh
return to it from um
return to it from uh from the bridge
from the bridge yeah right so uh what I
did like uh it's like race condition
where it verifies like uh the document
do domain or the window do location. so
I make a
redirect and that redirect takes a lot
of time and uh it would trick it onto
thinking that uh it's uh it has reach
that page it's all come for Full Circle
I mean it's making me think about the um
the thing that we're talking about the
beginning right yeah yeah it's similar
to the race condition the other cing
yeah yeah but this one in Mobile so
basically
uh yeah you you trick the bridge on
thinking that the origin was changed but
it wasn't time of check versus time of
use yeah yeah that's super super
interesting that's awesome I mean race
conditions on mobile usually don't
surface themselves in that way and it's
such a it's such an interesting
perspective to see like someone who's
like such a JavaScript like hacker come
and attack Mobile in like the same way
and so much of it just still works yeah
dude that's uh that's clutch man I love
anything relating to
delayed uh you know responses HTP
responses that's really there's there's
a couple scenarios in the browser as
well where you can manipulate or you you
need to have a specific set of requests
land in a specific order and so I've I
I've used uh delay in now with with um
seems like cookie being default uh all
these have to be top level navigations
so you what I'll often do is submit a
request into a different a post request
into a different tab delay the response
and then eventually 307 it to a
different location and then in that
meantime have the original tab do a top
level nav to a different endpoint so you
can get two top level navs off of one
click um which is helpful in those in
those scenarios yeah in this like uh
attack like how I delayed I just make a
a post request uh a post like uh
redirect with a post uh request so you
set the target to self and uh like make
the body like five megabytes or
something and it just keep uh waiting
like it take forever yeah oh wow
interesting yeah so oh but because
because well couldn't you also
so oh no because it has to be what what
origin are you sending the message to so
uh I don't
recall no but but like like because if
you're sending it to your own server you
could just do like a delayed HTTP
response right and then three it's not
it's not so what uh right so what this
uh the uh will do
uh okay it try it will try to send the
post message to that page okay but now
uh I send the post request to my uh to
the attacker page and would take a lot
of time yeah so there is a point where
it uh it fails to check that the page
has changed but it it didn't gotcha okay
I I see I see why you're doing the once
again the massive body of the the first
page is still loaded and everything but
it thinks that uh the second uh it it
actually redirected on that that makes
sense that makes sense wow um so many
things uh from this this episode that
are just kind of spinning around in my
head still um I I do have a place I want
to go next did you have something you
wanted to say on that I was just gonna
say the same thing I mean I I wish I
brought like a pad of sticky notes with
me because I'm like I'm like sitting
over here but I want to I'm like taking
notes in my head and I'm like I need to
write all these down when I'm done
luckily weing yeah I was going to say
we've got the recording we got our boy
uh our boy Brandon too gret me who's
doing the uh the hacker notes now so
we'll we'll get those there too make
sure you check those out by the way on
blog. criticalthinking podcast. um you
definitely need him for this episode
because there's a lot of a lot of
information I'm gonna have to get him
this episode early because it's going to
take him a long time to parse out
everything we've said here the last
thing that I kind of wanted to go into
here was you mentioned on your uh bug
Bounty reports explained interview and I
want to ALS oh just take the time now to
shout that interview out if you enjoy
this interview you will most definitely
enjoy that interview so um definitely
check out bug Bounty reports explained
uh interview with Yousef really great
content there you mentioned on that
interview that you use
um a water break get get your water get
your water Yousef come on this is this
is a chill thing um he's at like three
sips he he starts to reach part I say no
don't don't don't drink it I got a
question answer quick youf um no uh you
mentioned on that they use men and uh
mitm proxy I believe or maybe it's a
different I couldn't hear what you said
it kind of cut out right yeah and uh so
and you prefer to write your plugins in
that instead of yeah C could you talk a
little bit about what you use that for a
a little bit more in depth because you
mentioned on there you know there's
something about secrets and that sort of
thing but uh I imagine you're looking
for more specific things on specific
targets or is it more generic things and
are you parsing JavaScript with that or
are you looking at HTTP requests
specifically yeah so uh while I'm
browsing the in the in my browser I I'll
use mainly meum proxy and uh do an upst
stream Tober uh and Mum proxy will
basically uh save uh in time like
without delay the everything HTML pages
and the JavaScript uh files and all of
that and start doing work on that I
don't need like to wait for BB and after
that uh export it sporting that all of
that so while I'm navigating the things
work is being done in the background
that's and what kind of things yeah so
mainly share the secret this is critical
thinking podcast here Yousef we don't
just say we do things in the background
come on yeah so for example it extracts
few things from the HTML page uh oh did
I hear did I hear things from the HTML
yeah yeah are we are we are so we're you
know you from the HTML page so I imagine
you know this is these are things
specific to the current session or yeah
to the current session uh it's also
basic Recon for example uh in points
mentioned in HTML not in JavaScript ah
in JavaScript it also uh gets uh all the
in points and possibly sometimes the
parameters used to the request to that
point and it just shows them directly to
me and uh I'll just start testing I
don't need like to to uh so it's
basically uh scraping but uh it's
basically like having like uh uh
headless Chrome yeah it's like a scop
scraping because it's only for the stuff
that you're proxying and then use burps
and Upstream is that yeah yeah so I can
still check things manually that's cool
that's awesome um do you use those like
paths and stuff to create your own word
list or do you is that part of your con
flow at all or is it just you look for
the paths you test the paths and that's
kind of it yeah yeah that's got it cool
yeah I've never really used mum proxy
I'm not going to lie um I've seen it
used in in a couple different places for
like especially Hardware device proxying
I see a lot of people use it for that um
what are the the plugins written is it
like a bash or what is it no it's python
it's python oh awesome wow look at that
scripted changes HTP in Python that's
pretty sick it's it's like uh B but uh
in COD like you can you can uh do uh you
can even like at some point uh I thought
about having a graphical interface for
it and uh use it as burp but uh we had
we have burp so why exactly yeah no
there's definitely there's things
designed for that already this this is
really interesting though and I think
this could be useful as well now that um
kaido has Upstream stuff in place is if
you really need some sort of plugin for
your for your workflow you could
disjoint it from a specific thing like
burp ber kaido or anything like that so
you're able to be more flexible with
your proxy gooey and actually have you
know this as a lower level thing that
you're interacting directly with the
file system and you know I haven't used
this at all but I'm just looking briefly
over the docs right now and as as I was
prepping for this episode and it looks
really clean and simple yeah and it
gives you access to anything the request
and the response and everything it it
like that's what you need man all I need
is a request object a response object
like doesn't have to be that freaking
complex you know and then just let me do
something with that so that's uh that's
beautiful I understand why you use that
and I think that's probably a great
approach for any and and we've kind of
talked about this on the pot as well we
need to now we need to disjoint any
plugins that we're creating um from a
from burp and from kaido because kaido
has its problems right burp has its
problems and you know whichever you know
Arena you're in right now there's no
value you in creating something for one
when half of your environment is not
going to be able to use it so I think
using something creating it for like
something like mitm proxy could could
really allow you to just chain that
right into the upstream and then
disconnect from which proxy you're
actually going to be using and still
have access to all these plugins
hopefully hopefully kaido's uh kaido's
plug-in interface will come out soon
though that that is something that I
think they're very close to um so I
think that's all I had as far as
questions Joel did you have anything
else before you wanted to before we
close it off I mean unless he wants to
give me his social security number or
something I think I've asked everything
that's great well Yousef this is
definitely been one of the most
informative episodes we've ever had so
thank you so much for for sharing your
knowledge on all these different things
and these awesome uh uh bug stories I I
also have to say I'm very impressed with
your technical context window and how
much of these bug bug details you can
remember just sort of on the fly as
we're talking about it so um yeah thank
you so much for coming on and for
sharing all that uh thank you for having
me and uh yeah you're running a great
show thank you thank you and I I guess
you're on on Twitter you're uh Sam
samuda within zero right of yeah yeah
and then uh do you have any any other uh
socials you want to shout out yeah just
Twitter just Twitter all right go follow
him on Twitter guys and check out the
blog too y sam.com y.com yeah maybe
we'll see some more blogs there sometime
soon who knows maybe maybe all right
thanks man
thank w